Guide to the Florine Stettheimer Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series VII: Printed Material
  - Subseries VII.2: Catalogues
    - Fifth Annual Exhibition of the Society of Independent Artists, February 26-March 24, 1921, (Imcomplete ) (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - The First Retrospective Exhibition of American Art, Junior Art Patron's of America, May 6-21, 1921, (Incomplete ) (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - "Paintings and Drawings by American Artists showing the Later Tendencies in Art", Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts, Philadelphia, 1921? (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - Decorative Paintings at the Wanamaker Gallery of Modern Decorative Arts, Wanamaker Gallery, Belmaison, February 4-28, 1922, (partial ) (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - Sixth Annual Exhibition of the Society of Independent Artists, March 11-April 2, 1922, (partial ) (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - Modern Sculpture, Water Colors and Drawings at the Colony Club, New York, April 2-13, 1922, (partial ) (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - Salon D'Automne, 15eme Exposition, November 1-December 20, 1922, (partial ) (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - Annual American Exhibition at the Wanamaker Gallery of Modern Decorative Art, Wanamaker Gallery, Belmaison, January 22-February 17, 1923 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - Seventh Annual Exhibition of the Society of Independent Artists, February 24-March 18, 1923, (partial ) (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - Eighth Annual Exhibition of the Society of Independent Artists, March 7-30, 1924, (partial ) (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - Twenty-Third International Exhibition of Paintings at the Carnegie Institute, Pittsburgh, April 24-June 15, 1924, (partial ) (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - Twenty-Third Annual Exhibition of Modern Decorative Art at the Art Institute of Chicago, Art Institute, Chicago, December 23, 1924-January 25, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Society of Independent Artists, 1925, (partial ) (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - "One Hundred Important Paintings by Living American Artists", organized by the Arts Council of the City of New York, Architectural and Allied Arts Exposition, April 15-27, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Exhibition of The American Society of Painters, Sculptors and Gravers, Whitney Museum of American Art, February 6-28, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - First Biennial Exhibition of Contemporary American Painting, Whitney Museum of American Art, November 22, 1932-January 5, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Henry McBride "Florine Stettheimer", Museum of Modern Art, 1946, (3 ) (Box 3, Folder 22)
      [two hardcover; one paperback]
    - "Exhibition of Paintings by Florine Stettheimer", The Arts Club of Chicago, January 3-25, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Auction Catalogue, Parke-Bernet Galleries, Inc., March 22, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - "The Flowers of Florine Stettheimer", Durlacher Bros., New York, February 2-28, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - The Alfred Stieglitz Collection for Fisk University, The Carl Van Vechten Gallery of Fine Arts, Fisk University, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - "Fruits and Flowers in Painting: an exhibition spanning five centuries of art in the Western World", The Santa Barbara Museum of Art, August 12-September 14, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - "Florine Stettheimer: an Exhibition of Paintings, Watercolors, Drawings", Columbia University, February 8-March 8, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Elizabeth Sussman and Barbara Bloemink "Florine Stettheimer, Manhattan Fantastica", The Whitney Museum of Art, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - "American Paintings and Sculpture Pertaining to the War", M. Knoedler & Co., April 29-May 15 [n.d.] (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - Second Annual Decorative Exhibition in the Wanamaker Gallery of Modern Decorative Art, Belmaison, March 1-21 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
  - Subseries VII.3: Magazines and books
    - Marsden Hartley "The Paintings of Florine Stettheimer", Creative Art: a magazine of fine and applied art, 1931, (pp.19-23 ) (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Stettheimer's "West Point", Town & Country, May 1945, (1 cover) (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Parker Tyler "Stettheimer, Frances, Leonid, Tanguy", View: surrealism in Belgium, December 1946, (pp. 36-40 ) (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Henry McBride "Artists in the Drawing-Room" on the Stettheimer sisters, Town & Country, December 1946, (pp. 74-77 ) (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - The Stettheimer Doll's House presented to the Museum of the City of New York, Museum of the City of New York, June 12, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      [included with "The Laying of the Corner Stone of the Museum of the City of New York and the Building Fund list", April 30, 1929]
    - Carl Van Vechten "How I Remember Joseph Hergesheimer", Yale University Library Gazette, vol. 22, no. 3, January 1948, (pp. 87-93 ) (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Gifts to the University, University of California, January 1-December 31, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      [gift from Ettie Stettheimer]
    - The Avery Hopwood and Jule Hopwood Awards in Creative Writing, University of Michigan, August 29, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      [Including reproduction of Stettheimer portrait of Avery Hopwood]
    - A. Everett Austin Issue dedicated to A. Everett Austin, Jr., John and Mable Ringling Museum of Art, Wadsworth Atheneum, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      [Produced 4 Saints in 3 Acts in 1934]
    - The Minneapolis Institute of Arts, June 1960, (Calendar) (Box 4, Folder 11)
      [Including mention of acquisition of Stettheimer's "Portrait of our Nurse, Mary Burgess"]
    - Clifford Wright Helten I den nye verden: 12 kapitler om amerikansk kunst-fra en kunsters synspunkt, 1963, (book) (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Subseries VII.4: Clippings and articles
    - "Miss Stettheimer's Oils", American Art News, October 21, 1916 (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - W.G. Bowdoin "Miss Florine Stettheimer at Knoedler's", the Brooklyn Evening World, October 21, 1916 (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - Article, New York Evening Mail, October 21, 1916 (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - Article, New York Evening Post, October 21, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Article, New York Evening Post, October 21, 1916 (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - Article, Brooklyn Eagle, October 22, 1916 (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - Frederick W. Eddy "Panel Painting, Suggestive of a Fresco of Period of Louis XVI", The World, Sunday, October 22, 1916 (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - "Paintings and Prints Open", New York Times Magazine, October 22, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Article, New York Tribune, October 24, 1916 (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - Henry McBride Article, New York Sun, April 28, 1918 (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - Article, New York Herald Tribune, May 5, 1918 (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - "Paintings and Sculptures of War one of Several Interesting Arts Shows", New York Herald, May 5, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - "Portraits of Men in Service", the Brooklyn Eagle, May 5, 1918 (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - "Notes on Current Art", New York Times, 1919 (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - Hamilton Easter Field "Society of Independent Artists at the Waldorf", The Brooklyn Daily Eagle?, 1919 (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - "Mrs. Whitney's Art Gift", New York Herald Sun, March 30, 1920 (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - Article, Brooklyn Eagle, March 28, 1920 (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - James Gibbons Huneker "Too Proud to Paint, Independent Idea", New York World, March 20, 1920 (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - Article, New York American, March 14, 1920 (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - S. Jay Kaufman "Round the Town", The Globe, March 20,1920 (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - Hamilton Easter Field "The Arts", April, 1921 (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - Henry McBride "Independent Art Show Teaches a Moral Lesson", New York Sun's Herald, [n.d.] (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - "Independents' Art Show Voluminous", New York Evening Post, February ?, 1921 (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - "Art Independents Hang Cubists High", New York[?], [n.d.] (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - Henry McBride "Bronze Shows How Mrs. Harry Payne Whitney Had Cubism Thrust Upon Her", New York Herald, March 6, 1921 (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - Matthew Lorden "Why One Artist Became a Modernist", New York Evening World, March 20, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - David Lloyd "Radical Artists Show Their Work", New York Evening Post, April 16, 1921 (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - Bushnell Dimond "Boredom Banished by the Modernists", The Philadelphia Inquirer, April 17, 1921 (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - Henry McBride "Old Academy Housing Exhibition of Many Phases of Modern Art", The New York Herald, April 17, 1921 (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - "Mantels and Over Mantels on View", New York Herald, April 17, 1921 (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - H. Field? "At the Pennsylvania Academy", Brooklyn Eagle, 1921 (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
      [partial]
    - "World of Art":Later Tendencies at the Philadelphia Exhibition", New York Times Book Review and Magazine, April 24, 1921 (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - Article, New York Evening Post, April 30, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Paul Rosenfeld "The Academy Opens Its Doors", New Republic, May 4, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - "American Society Opens Art Display at Whitney Gallery", New York Herald, October 23, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - "Arts Building Stops Dance, So 500 Go to Lewisohn's", New York Herald, May 7, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Stanley Olmstead "'Junior Patrons' to Develop New Army of Art Buyers", New York Evening Mail, May 14, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - "Decorators at Wanamaker's", American Art News, February 18, 1922 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - Illustration of decorative panel by Florine Stettheimer, The Brooklyn Daily Eagle, February 19, 1922 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - Hamilton Easter Field "At Wanamaker's", [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - David Lloyd "Wanamaker's", New York Evening Post, February 25, 1922 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - "'Scrambled Art' Exhibited in Tempermental Riot", Philadelphia Evening Public Ledger, March 11, 1922 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - "Independent Show Has Grown Serious", American Art News, March 11, 1922 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - "Art Review", [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - David Lloyd "Independents Like Public's Ridicule", New York Evening Post, March 13, 1922 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - "Studio and Gallery", New York Sun, March 18, 1922 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - "Public Finds Some Art of Independents Quite Worth While", [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - "Independent Artists as Amusing as Ever", New York Herald, March 19, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      [complete in Journal no. 6]
    - "Independent Artists as Amusing as Ever", New York Herald, March 19, 1922 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - "Modernists Form New Artist Society", American Art News, March 25, 1922 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - Penelope Redd "Daily Life Incidents are Taken for Stettheimer Decorations; Skill, Pity, Mockery Combined", Pittsburgh Post, April 2, 1922 (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
      [See also: Journal. No. 6. Partial in scrapbook no. 1 and complete in Journal no. 6]
    - "Review", New York Times, April 9, 1922 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - Henry Tyrrell "Significant Form, Line, Color in Recent Shows of Modern Art", April 16,1922 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Henry Tyrrell "Significant Form, Line, Color in Recent Shows of Modern Art", April 16,1922 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - Henry McBride "Notable Display of Contemporary French works in the Sculptors' Gallery and the Colony Club Houses Pictures by Some of the Liveliest Americans", April 22, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Henry McBride "Notable Display of Contemporary French works in the Sculptors' Gallery and the Colony Club Houses Pictures by Some of the Liveliest Americans", April 22, 1922 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - "The Fine Arts: Modern Arts in Worcester", The Boston Evening Transcript, April 30, 1922 (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - Baron de Meyer Silhouettes and coiffure notes, Harper's Bazaar, August, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Henry McBride "Art News and Reviews", New York Herald, February 25, 1923 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
      [missing article]
    - "Studio and Gallery", New York Sun, March 3, 1923 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - Henry McBride "Striking Exhibition of the Independents: Usual Giddy Throng Attends Annual Show at Waldorf", New York Herald, March 4, 1923 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - "Where Two Thousand Artists Strive for Recognition", Arts & Decoration, March 1923 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - Alexander Brook Blurb, 1923? (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - Margaret Breuning "Pleasing Exhibit by Independent Artists", 1923? (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - "Independents Artists' Exhibition", Christian Science Monitor, March 7, 1923 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - Fanny Butcher Blurb, Chicago Daily Tribune, March 10, 1923? (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - "Decorative Art", New York Evening Post, March 10, 1923 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - Article, New York Sun, March 10, 1923 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - "Decorative Art Exhibit at Wanamaker Galleries", New York Herald, March 11, 1923 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - Burton Rascoe "Book News and Reviews", New York Tribune, March 11, 1923 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - R.F. "Decorative Art in New York", Christian Science Monitor, March 12, 1923 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - Henry McBride "City of New York As Seen by the Artists", New York Herald, May 27, 1923 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - Henry McBride "The New Gallery on Madison Avenue arranges an exhibition", New York Herald, May 13, 1923 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - Steichen, photographer "Callot and Paquin Creations for the Evening Mode", Vogue, September 1923 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
      [Screen behind model by Florine Stettheimer]
    - Henry McBride "Barrau's Spanish Sunlight Pictures Attract Attention", New York Herald, November 18, 1923 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - Burton Rascoe "A Bookman's Day Book", New York Tribune, November 25, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Henry McBride "Independent Art Has Vivid Opening: Nudes Seem in Style Again, Says Visitor at Exhibition", New York Herald, Sunday, Nov ?, 1923? (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - "Mr. and Mrs. Rodolph Valentino"(draped over Stettheimer painting), Vanity Fair, November 1923 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      [Reverse of Callot and Paquin photo]
    - Steichen, photographer Models posed in front of Stettheimer works, [n.p.], [1923?], (3 ) (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Guy Pene Du Bois "A Notable Exhibition by Modern Decorative Artists", Vogue, 1923? (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - "Independent Show Taking Shape", The Sun, [n.d.] (1924?) (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Peyton Boswell "Independent Art Exhibit Opens to Throngs", New York American, March 8, 1924 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - Forbes Watson "Art News of the Week: the Pittsburgh International", The World, April 27, 1924 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - Kenelm Digby (Rose Benet?) "The Literary Lobby", The Literary Review, May 3, 1924 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - Nina Carey? "The World of Art: the Pittsburgh International Exhibition", New York Times Magazine, May 4, 1924 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - Penelope Redd "Paintings from International Selected for Tour", Pittsburgh Sunday Post, May 11, 1924 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - Henry McBride "American Artists Make Poor Showing in Pittsburgh Exhibit", New York Sun?, 1924? (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - "Old and New Pictures of Flowers Make Fine Effect at Belmaison", New York World, January, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Henry McBride "Art Show Hope of 'Unknowns'", New York Sun, March 21, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Henry McBride "Art Show Hope of 'Unknowns'", New York Sun, March 21, 1925 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - Elinor Wylie "Profiles in Black Paint, With a Very Sparing Use of Whitewash", New Yorker, March 19, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      [Illustration by Peter Arno]
    - Henry McBride? "Independents Take on Years: tenth annual display finds them still rescuing unknowns from oblivion", New York Sun, March 13, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Illustration of 'Heat' by Florine Stettheimer (Allied Arts Exposition), New York Evening Post, March 30, 1929 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - "Women Artists Occupy Important Place in Exposition of Architectural League", NY Telegram, April 15, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - "Announce '100 Significant Paintings' for New York Show", Chicago Post, April 16, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Henry McBride "All Arts of Present Day Are Represented in Vast Display", New York Sun, April 20(?)1929 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - "Two Large Exhibitions", New York Times, April 21, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - "100 Important Paintings at Grand Central Palace; Shown by Arts Council", Brooklyn Eagle, April 21, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - "Art in Des Moines", Des Moines, Iowa Register, May 19, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Henry McBride "Modern Art"(concerning 100 Important Paintings), [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Ralph Flint "Whitney Museum Host to Lively Group Exhibition", The Art News, February 13, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Edward Alden Jewell "In the Realm of Art: Important Current Shows", New York Times, Sunday, February 14, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - "In Lighter Vein", The Art News, February 27, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Paul Rosenfeld "The World of Florine Stettheimer", The Nation, May 4, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Henry McBride "$20,000 Purchase Fun Leads to Gay and Vivacious Display", New York Sun, Saturday, November 26, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - "Attractions in Other Galleries"(Whitney Show), 1932? (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Henry McBride "Chicago's Art Emphasizes Good Taste rather than any Special Virility", New York Sun, Saturday, March 4, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Article, Herald (Whitestone, NY), January 10, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - "Avery Exhibition of American Art Opens January 29", Hartford (CT) Courant, January 22, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - "American Art Showing Will Feature at Avery", Hartford (CT) Times, January 25, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Henry McBride "The Museums Reopen", May 27, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Carlyle Burrows "The Week in Art", New York Tribune, November 11, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Paul Rosenfeld "Florine Stettheimer", Accent, Winter, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - "Vogue Spotlight", Vogue, September 15, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Carl Van Vechten "The World of Florine Stettheimer", Harper's Bazaar, October, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - "Florine", New Yorker, October 1, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - "A Stranger Here Herself", Newsweek, October 14, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - "Something to Talk About", Newsweek, October 1946 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - MOMA Exhibition, New York, 1946, (Fragment ) (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Henry McBride "Artists in the Drawing Room", Town & Country, December, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Thalia "Chicagoans Enjoy Exhibit at Arts Club", Chicago Sunday Tribune, January 12, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Eleanor Jewett "Art Exhibits for January Entertaining", Chicago Sunday Tribune, January 12, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Emily Genauer, editor "Flower Paintings Gay", NY World- Telegram, February 10, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Henry McBride "Water Colors Preferred, etc. Attractions in the Galleries", New York Sun, February 6, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Carlyle Burrows "Art Exhibition Opens as Tribute to Henry McBride", 1949 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Monroe Wheeler "Soutine", Harper's Bazaar, November 1950 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Cholly Knickerbocker "Wanger's Pot-Shots Queered His Chances of Inheriting Millions as His Aunt Already Had Frowned on His Marriage to Joan Bennett", New York Journal-American, December 20, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Four Saints in Three Acts at the Broadway Theatre, [New York], 1952, (Newspaper advertisement) (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Sam Zolotow "'Four Saints in Three Acts' will open tonight", April 16, 1952? (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Brooks Atkinson "'Four Saints in Three Acts" restaged by ANTA at the Broadway Theatre", New York Times, April 17, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Robert Sylvester "'Four Saints in Three Acts' Again: musical, mystical and very funny", 1952? (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - William Hawkins "'Four Saints in Three Acts' Takes Curtain Call", 1952? (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - "Doll Houses", Newsweek, March 16, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Edouard Roditi "The Fate of Otto Freundlich, painter 'maudit'", Commentary, September 1955 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Art Students League News, vol. 10, no. 4, April 1957 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Notice of acquisition of Stettheimer's "Portrait of our Nurse, Mary Burgess", Minneapolis Institute of Arts, June 1960 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Edward M. Potoker "Eccentrics in a Mirage", New York Times Book Review, June 2, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - "People are Talking About", Vogue, November 1, 1963? (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - "The Galleries-a Critical Guide", New York Herald Tribune, November 2, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Stuart Preston "Major Art Events by Renaissance Masters: Some Contemporaries", New York Times, November 3, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - "Florine Stettheimer", Arts Magazine, December 1963 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - "Florine Stettheimer", Art News, December 1963 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - John Gruen "Golden Stage, Silver Screen", November 10, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Paul Picknel "Harper's New Books", January 1964 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - St.-Clair McKelway "Up on the Flying Trapeze; Snow and Slush; Is Hopkins Outmoded? $215, 600 for a Monet", New Yorker, April 4, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Allen Hughes "In Virgil Thomson's Rooms, Style Reigns", New York Times, Sunday, April 16, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Frank Merkling "Witty '20s, '30s portraits in Katonah", News-Times (Danbury, CT), September 12, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Two New Shows at the Katonah (NY) Museum, "Friends and Family: Portraiture in the World of Florine Stettheimer", Weekend Magazine, September 15-16, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - "Katonah, Neuberger museums to mount major exhibitions", The Scarsdale Inquirer, Friday August 20, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - "KMA Exhibit Examines the Portrait", Trader Weekend, September 16, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Jeannette Ross "Faces Take Their Places at Museum", The Lewisboro Ledger, Thursday, September 23, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - "Florine Stettheimer has her day", Hudson Valley, September, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - "Stettheimer Exhibition", New York Times, Sunday, September 19, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Stettheimer exhibition at Katonah, NewYork Magazine, September 13, 1993, (Notice ) (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Roberta Smith "The Very Rich Hours of Florine Stettheimer", New York Times, Sunday, October 10, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Vivien Raynor "A Rogues' Gallery of Artists and Esthetes", New York Times, Sunday, October 24, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Ingrid Schaffner "The World of Florine Stettheimer", Art & Antiques, December 1993 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - "Salute to Katonah Museum of Art", 1994? (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Stettheimer painting (the Picnic?) from a magazine, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - "Mrs. John Lavern als Bild von Botticelli", [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - "Two Gifts to Museum Attract Attention" (Portland Art Museum), [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Howard Devree "Modern Masters", New York Times, Sunday, [n.d.] (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Palle Klaer Stephensen "Kunstpause hos Elsa Gress", [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - "The Grand Old Man Creates a Stir" (Elsa Gress and Clifford Wright), [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - James Thrall Soby "The Fine Arts: the Karolik Collection at Boston", [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - "Wadsworth Atheneum Given Florine Stettheimer Painting, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - 14 article fragments, 1920s? (Box 4, Folder 20)